[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
&gt;&gt; 早上好
Welcome to Session 227, Data
欢迎来到227会场的主题会议
Delivery with Drag and Drop.
通过拖放传输数据
My name is Dave Rahardja, and
我是 Dave Rahardja
I'm joined here, today, by my
今天
colleague Tanu, who's going to
我和同事 Tanu 来给大家讲解
be operating the demos.
她将给大家做演示
So, if you've been following
如果大家一直在关注
along in our series of Drag and
我们的拖放主题会议
Drop sessions, this diagram
那么这张图表
should be pretty familiar to
对你来说肯定非常
you.
熟悉
During this session, we're going
在这次会议中
to be focusing on this part of
我们将重点讨论图表上的这一部分
the diagram, Item Providers.
Item Provider
Now, Item Providers are
目前 Item Provider
fundamental to the way data is
对于使用拖放功能实现
transferred between applications
应用之间的数据传输方式来说
in drag and drop.
是它的关键基础
So, in this session, we're going
所以 在这次会议中
to cover four topics about item
我们将覆盖四个有关 Item Provider
providers.
的主题
We're going to cover some
我们要谈的是一些
basics.
基础内容
We're going to talk about how
包括统一类型的标识符如何
uniform type identifiers help
帮助你的 App
your apps to be more compatible
与系统中的
with others in the system.
其他 App 更加兼容
We're going to cover how you can
我们还会谈到如何
create model classes that work
创建模型类  让它们真正能够
really well with drag and drop.
与拖放功能进行良好结合
And finally, we're going to
最后 我们将以
close out by covering some
一些高端主题作为结束
advanced topics that'll add some
这些主题可以切实改进
real polish to your apps in our
我们行业生态中的
ecosystem.
App 状况
So, let's get started.
现在我们就直奔主题
Let's talk about some
先聊一聊
NSItemProvider basics.
NSItemProvider 的基本状况
So, what's an NSItemProvider?
NSItemProvider 是什么
Simply put, an NSItemProvider is
简单来说 一个 NSItemProvider
a data promise.
就是一个数据承诺
All data is loaded through drag
所有数据都是根据需要
and drop asynchronously and on
通过拖放而完成
demand.
异步加载的
An NSItemProvider can also, help
NSItemProvider 也可以
you to provide progress and
为你提供数据传输的
cancellation of data transfer.
进度和取消操作
And it is supported widely in
它广泛应用于
our API.
我们的 API 中
Of course, in drag and drop, but
当然 也广泛应用于拖放
also in UIPasteConfiguration.
和 UIPasteConfiguration 当中
And we've added API for
我们已经为 UIPasteboard
UIPasteboard, so that you can
新增了 API  这样你就可以
use NSItemProvider directly with
直接使用 NSItemProvider
So, what does it mean to provide
那么 提供数据或承诺数据
data or promise data?
指的是什么呢
Providing data to an
向 NSItemProvider 提供数据
NSItemProvider is really simple.
其实十分简单
All you have to do is create an
你所要做的就是
NSItemProvider and pass it an
创建一个 NSItemProvider
object that is suitable for use.
然后 向它传递一个适用的对象
Now, a lot of our system
现在 我们有许多
provided classes, such as
系统提供的分类
UIImage in a string, in its
例如字符串中的 UIImage
attributed string can be used
在它的属性字符串里
this way.
就可以这样使用
And we'll see in a few slides
我们现在来看几张幻灯片
now, how you can make your
看看通过哪些步骤
classes work in this fashion, as
能让你的分类以同样的方式
well.
运行
Once you provide the data, it
只要你提供数据  它就可以
can be retrieved by the
被接收的应用程序获取
receiving application equally
获取形式同样也很简单
simply, by calling the
它只需要从中调用
loadObject method on the
itemProvider 上的
itemProvider, therein.
loadObject 方法就可以
Remember that data transfer is
记住  这种数据传输
asynchronous and that your
是异步的  此外
completionHandlers will be
你的 CompletionHandler
called on a nonmain cue.
将在一个非主队列被调用
So, if you're going to update
所以 如果你要使用接收的数据
the UI with your received data,
更新用户界面
be sure to dispatch back to the
请确定在调用 UIKit 方法之前
main queue before you call UIKit
你已经调度回到
methods.
主队列
And you're going to see this
你会看到  这种情况
brought up a few times.
会出现好几次
So, to show you how easy it is
那么 为了让大家知道
to use NSItemProviders, we're
操作 NSItemProviders 多么容易
going to start with a demo.
我们先来看一个演示
Tanu.
有请 Tanu
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Good morning, everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家早上好
You've now heard of drag and
你们刚刚已经听说了拖放功能
drop and NSItemProviders.
和 NSItemProvider
But now, you're probably
现在 你们可能想了解
wondering how to use these in
如何把它们应用到
your own apps.
自己的 App 中
My name is Tanu Singhal, and
我是 Tanu Singhal
I'll show you a simple demo that
我将为大家做一个简单的演示
will help you get started with
它将帮助你们初步了解
NSItemProviders.
NSItemProvider
We have an app, here, that has a
现在 我们有一个 App
list of customers for our
它里面有我们产品
product.
的客户名单
Now, I met some new people who
现在 我刚遇到其他一些人
are also interested in trying
他们也有兴趣试试
out this product.
这款产品
So, I noted their names down in
所以 我把他们的名字
Reminders.
添加到提醒事项中
It would be nice if could drag a
如果我能把名字直接拖放到
name and drop it into my app.
我的 App 里 那就太好了
So, how do we do this?
那我们应该怎么操作呢
Let's look at the
我们来看一下
TableViewController for our
这个联系人 App 使用的
Contacts app.
的 TableViewController
Before I start typing I want you
在我开始输入之前
to know that we made the sample
我希望你们知道
code for this available on the
我们已经把这个示例代码
developer website.
放在了开发者网站上
So, you don't have to worry
所以大家不用担心
about jotting down everything,
不需要现在就把所有代码
right now.
都抄下来
In the TableViewController, I'll
在 TableViewController 里 我要
add a TableViewDropDelegate.
添加一个 TableViewDropDelegate
Let's also set this delegate.
还要对这个委托进行设置
You may have heard of the
大家可能已经在此前的
TableViewDropDelegate in
会议里听到过
previous sessions.
TableViewDropDelegate了
But if you haven't, then don't
如果没有听说过的话
worry.
也不用担心
Because for now, we only need to
因为我们现在只需要
implement one method called
执行一种方法  名叫
TableView performDropWith
TableView performDropWith
coordinator.
coordinator
In this method, I'll iterate
在这个方法里
over the drag items provided by
我会对 ItemProvider
the ItemProvider.
提供的拖动项进行迭代
Sorry, the dragItems provider by
对不起 应该是协调器提供的
the coordinator.
拖动项
Now, each dragItem has its own
现在 每个拖动项都有自己的
itemProvider.
itemProvider
And we can check whether the
我们可以测试一下
itemProvider can load objects of
itemProvider 是否可以加载
a certain type.
某一具体类型的对象
So, I'm going to check if the
那么 我就来测试
itemProvider can load a string.
itemProvider 是否可以加载字符串
For that, I'll call the
这样的话  我将调用
canLoadObject method.
canLoadObject 方法
If it can load it, then I'll
如果它可以加载
call the loadObject method.
那我就调用 loadObject 方法
And the completionHandler of
然后 这个 loadObject 方法的
this loadObject method will give
completionHandler 将会
me an object which will be a
给我一个对象 也就是字符串
string that I can use to update
这样我就可以用它来更新
my data models, as well as my
我的数据模型以及
UI.
我的用户界面
One thing to note is that the
需要注意的是
completionHandler is on the
completionHandler 位于
background thread.
后台线程上
So, if you want to make any
因此 如果你想在你的用户界面上
changes to your UI, then you
进行任何更改
need to go back to the main
你需要回到主线程上
thread, and then make those
然后再做这样一些
changes.
更改
So, let me dispatch my main
那么 我先来调度我的
queue.
主队列
And in the main thread I'll use
在主线程中 我将
the string object, and I'll
使用字符串对象
insert it into the TableView.
把它插入到 TableView 中
This code is ready to run, now.
这个代码现在可以运行了
Wait just a moment.
再稍等一下
And this time, I can drag a name
这一次 我可以把一个人的名字
from Reminders and drop it into
从提醒事项拖出来放到
my app.
我的 App 里了
The canLoadObject and LoadObject
canLoadObject 和 LoadObject 方法
methods can also be used for
同样可以应用于
other system types, like
其他的系统类型 例如
attributed strings, URLs,
带属性的字符串 URL
images, and even colors.
图像  甚至是颜色
So, now that you've seen how
那么 现在大家已经看到
straightforward it is to handle
在 itemProvider 里处理
system objects in your using
系统对象是有多么简单直接
itemProviders, I would encourage
我建议各位都去
all of you to try out these
尝试一下这些
APIs.
API
Up next, Dave will talk about
接下来 Dave 会讲解
Progress and Cancellation.
进度与取消
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Tanu.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Tanu
So, that covers the basics about
进度与取消  涉及到关于
how to use NSItemProviders in
如何在应用里使用 NSItemProviders
your application.
的基础问题
It was really simple.
其实十分简单
Now, let's talk about progress
那我们就来谈谈进度
and cancellation.
以及取消
When you retrieve data using
当你使用 NSItemProviders
NSItemProviders, we return a
检索数据时
progress object to you that
我们会向你返回一个进度对象
allows you to track the progress
通过它 你就可以在数据传输时
of data transfer as it occurs.
跟踪传输进度
The progress object has two
这个进度对象
interesting properties on it,
包含了两个有趣的属性
that you might want to observe.
你可能想了解一下
The first, is the
第一个属性
fractionCompleted property,
是 fractionCompleted 属性
which tells you from zero to
它的值为0到1
one, how much of the data has
它会告诉你目前数据的
been transferred.
传输量已经有多少
And the second, is an isFinished
第二个是 isFinished 属性
property that tells you that the
它会告诉你
data transfer has been
数据传输已经完成
completed, whether it is
以及传输结果
successful or not.
是否成功
You can use key value observing
你可以用键值观察
to watch these two properties
来查看这两个属性
and update your UI accordingly.
并相应地更新你的用户界面
Such as by providing your own
例如设置自己的
progress indicator and
进度指示器和
cancellation button.
取消按钮
There is a cancel method on the
此外 在进度对象中有一个
progress object that will
取消方法
immediately cancel the data
它可以立即取消
transfer, as well.
数据传输
When you call he cancel method
当你在返回进度对象上
on the return progress object,
调用取消方法时
your receiving application will
你的接收应用
receive, will get a callback on
会在 completionHandler 上
the completionHandler with an
接收到一个有错误的回调函数
error in it, regardless of
而不论
whether or not the source
源应用程序是否
application has cancelled their
已经取消
data providing.
其数据提供行为
You get one progress object per
你每一次提出加载请求
load request.
都会获得一个进度对象
However, there's an overall
不过 你也可以从 UIDropSession
progress object that you can get
获取一个整体进度对象
from the UIDropSession that
以便监控和取消
allows you to monitor and cancel
该进度中
the entire remaining data
所有剩余的
transfer in progress.
数据传输任务
So, now that we've covered the
好 既然我们已经讲过了
basics, let's talk about
基础知识  那么我们再来谈一谈
maximizing compatibility.
兼容性的最大化
You want your application to
大家都希望自己的应用
provide data to as many other
可以尽可能向系统里的
applications on the system, as
其他更多的应用程序
possible.
提供数据
And receive drops from as many
同时也从尽可能多的
applications, as possible, as
应用程序里接收到点滴汇集的
well.
数据
The key to understanding how to
理解兼容性的最大化途径
maximize compatibility is
关键在于理解
understanding uniform type
同一类型的
identifiers.
标识符
So, let's recap.
那么我扼要重述一下
One NSItemProvider represents
一个 NSItemProvider 代表
one thing that the user is
用户在不同类之间
dragging across the glass.
拖动的项目
However, there can be multiple
但是 你可以给
representations that you can
用户拖动的
make available for every item
每一个项目
that the user is dragging.
设置多种表示方法
Let me give you an example.
我给大家举个例子
If you're writing a vector
比如说你准备编写一个
drawing program, for example,
矢量绘图程序
you could offer a native file
你可以提供本地文件格式
format for best quality as the
以便让你拖动的项目
thing that you're dragging.
保持最佳质量
But you might also offer
但事实上 你也可能会
conversions to PDF, PNG, or even
将其转换为 PDF PNG
JPG, so that you can drop this
甚至 JPG 格式  这样你就可以
item on a variety of destination
将这个项目拖到各种
applications.
目标应用当中
Uniform type identifiers allow
统一类型标识符可以
you to tag these representations
让你给这些表示方法
with unique strings that
加上特殊字符串的标记
identify the kinds of data that
以便识别出你将要
you're putting up for the drag.
拖动的数据类型
For a native file format, you
对于本地文件格式
can define your own strings,
你可以自定义它的字符串
such as
例如
com.yourcompany.vector-drawing.
com.yourcompany.vector-drawing
And for commonly known types,
而对于一些常见类型
such as PDF and PNG, you can use
例如 PDF 和 PNG 你可以
the symbols defined in mobile
使用 MobileCoreServices 里
core services to tag them.
的定义符号来标记它们
Now, fidelity order matters.
现在看来  真正起作用的是精准顺序
The order in which you register
你的各种表示方法
your representations should
它们的登记顺序
correspond to the order of
应该和你准备向目标提供的
quality that you're making
质量要求顺序
available to the destination.
相互一致
Usually, the highest fidelity
通常情况下 最高精准度
would be your internal data
可以是你的内部数据
representation type.
表示类型
And then, followed by the next
紧接着的 是下一个高精准度的
high fidelity common type, and
普通类型
so on and so forth.
以此类推
Now, one tip to remember when
现在  有一个小提示需要大家记住
using type identifiers to
当你使用类型标识符
register your representations,
来记录自己的表示方法时
is that there are uniform type
要有各种同类型的标识符
identifiers that correspond to
它们应当与各种抽象类型
abstract types.
相匹配
Such as data, or plain text, or
例如数据  纯文本
image.
或者图像
Avoid these.
不要使用这些方式
Instead, use concrete data types
而是要使用具体数据类型
that help the consumer of your
它们能帮助你的数据使用者
data interpret the bytes that
解译你将要
you're going to send over to
发送给他们的
them.
字节
So, for example, use
那么 我们举个例子
utf8-plain-text, instead of
使用 UTF-8 编码的纯文本
plain-text.
而不是纯文本
Or probably .png instead of
或者 也可以用 .png 代替
image, so that the receiver can
“图像” 这样接收器就可以
interpret your data.
解译你的数据
Of course, for your private type
当然 对于大家个人使用的类型标识符
identifier, you're free to
你也可以自由地
define your own data types and
界定数据类型和
byte layouts.
字节布局
So, you've seen how these
那么 大家已经看到
multiple representations allow
这些多重表示方法
you to maximize compatibility.
如何帮助你实现兼容性的最大化
But you didn't see any of this
但是你并没有看见
type identifiers being used in
这些类型标识符里有哪一种被用于
our initial example code of
我们起初提供的创建 NSItemProviders 的
creating NSItemProviders.
示例代码中
So, how did this work together?
那么 这是怎样运行起来的呢
This is where we talk about
这就是我们要讨论的
creating model classes that
创建模型分类
harness the power of both
它们利用这两种
multiple representations for
多重表示的潜能
compatibility.
来实现兼容
And the simplicity of using
还有  通过使用对象来实现
objects to initialize
itemProviders 初始化
itemProviders.
的简易性
To create model classes that
为了创建可以跟拖放功能
work well with drag and drop,
良好结合的模型分类
we're going to talk about two
我们将要谈论两种协议
protocols that help you to do
它们会帮助你做到
this.
这一点
NSItemProviderReading and
NSItemProviderReading 和
NSItemProviderWriting.
NSItemProviderWriting
Let's talk about the writing
我们先来谈谈
protocol, first.
编写协议
NSItemProviderWriting exports
NSItemProviderWriting
data from your model object and
从你的模型对象中输出数据
NSItemProviderReading imports
而 NSItemProviderReading 则输入数据
data and creates a model object
并且从一种表示方式中
from a representation.
创建一个模型对象
And by adopting these protocols,
通过接受这些协议
you can maintain the conversion
你可以使用自己的模型对象
between your model objects and
而不是UI代码
multiple representations with
来保证你的模型对象
your model object and not with
与多重表示方法这两者间的
the UI code.
转换
So, let's take a look at
那么 我们一起看一下
NSItemProviderWriting.
NSItemProviderWriting
This is what it looks like.
这就是它的样子
There are only two things that
要想遵循这个协议
you need to implement to conform
你只需运行两个对象
to this protocol.
就可以了
The first is a
第一个就是
writableTypeIdentifiersForItem
writableTypeIdentifiersForItemProvider
Provider property.
属性
This is the list of the type
这是你可以
identifiers that you can export
按照精准顺序输出的
in fidelity order.
类型标识符列表
Highest fidelity first.
首先是最高精准度
And then, a loadData method
然后 是一种 loadData 方法
which will take that
它将使用
typeIdentifier that has been
其他应用已经
requested by the other
请求过的
application.
类型标识符
Which will call a
这将会调用一个
completionHandler, either with
completionHandler 以及
the data that you've made
你所提供的数据  这数据要么
available or with an error.
可以使用  要么有错误
By implementing this protocol,
通过执行这个协议
the UI code can look like this
UI代码可以变成这样
and our framework code will do
而我们的框架代码
the equivalent of this, for you.
同时也会为你做出类似的事
All right.
好了
Let's take a look at the reading
我们来看一下
protocol.
读取协议
The reading protocol is, of
当然 读取协议
course, the other end of the
是问题的另一
pipe.
方面
It too, has two things that you
它也有两样事情  需要你来
need to implement.
执行
The first is the list of
第一个是
readable type identifiers in
按照精准度排序的
fidelity order, also.
可读类型标识符的列表
And the second, is that
第二个是
initializer that will take a NS
初始化程序
data block, a NS data object,
它使用一个 NS 数据块  NS 数据对象
which should be used to
这个对象应是被用来
initialize the instance of your
初始化你的
object.
对象实例
When you implement this protocol
当你执行这项协议时
the UI code can look like this,
UI 代码会变成这样
a canLoadObject.
一个 canLoadObject
You can pass it to your vector
你可以将它传输到你的
drawing object.
矢量绘图对象上
And when you call the
当你调用 loadObject 时
loadObject, our framework code
我们的框架代码
will matchmake the two lists of
将会匹配来自
type identifiers, both from the
提供方和使用方的
provider and the consumer.
两列类型标识符
To find the best match to ensure
为了寻找最佳匹配
that the highest quality data is
以期保证能够使用
used to create an instance of
最高质量的信息
your object.
来创建你的对象实例
So, in short, to make model
简而言之 为了创建
classes that work well with drag
能与拖放功能良好结合的
and drop, you should create,
模型分类  你应该创建
these classes should conform to
这些分类应该遵循
NSItemProvider reading and
NSItemProvider 读取和
writing protocols.
编写协议
Because these are Objective-C
因为这些都是 Objective-C
protocols, your model classes
协议 你的模型分类
should also inherit from
应该也是从
NSObject.
NSObject 承继而来
And when you do this, you can
当你这样操作的时候
use your classes and your
你可以在任何支持
objects wherever NSItemProvider
NSItemProvider 的程序里
is supported, drag and drop, and
使用你的分类和对象
UIPasteConfiguration, and also,
包括拖放  UIPasteConfiguration 以及
with the new API in
新增了API的
UIPasteboard.
UIPasteboardUIPasteboard
So, to show you how this is done
因此 为了向大家展示
in code, I'm going to ask Tanu
如何在代码中实现这一点
to do another demo.
我将有请 Tanu 再次进行演示
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Hello, again.
&gt;&gt;  大家好  我又来了
In the previous demo, we learned
在上一个演示中 我们了解到
to load simple system objects
如何加载简单的系统对象
like strings.
比如字符串
Now, let's see how we can drag a
现在 我们来看看
rich contact card from the
怎样把一张复杂的名片
Contacts app and drop that into
从联系人 App 拖到
our app.
我们自己的 App 里
To do this, I've created a class
为了实现这个操作 我已经创建了一个分类
called ContactCard.
叫作 ContactCard
This holds the name, phone
它包含联系人的姓名
number, and photo for a contact.
电话号码以及照片
Now, I'm going to go back into
现在 我将回到
the TableView controller, and
TableViewController
this is the performDrop method
这是我们之前运行的
that we implemented, before.
performDrop方法
Last time, we were trying to
我们上次演示的是
load a string.
加载字符串
Now, we want to load a contact
而这次 我们想要
card.
加载一张联系人名片
So, I'll replace all instances
所以 我将用 ContactCard
of NSSTring with ContactCard.
代替所有 NSString 中的实例
Since we are requesting a
因为我们请求的是
contact card the
一张联系人名片
completionHandler will directly
所以 completionHandler 将会直接
give me a contact card object,
给我一个联系人名片对象
and I can use that to insert
我就可以把它
into my TableView.
插入到我的 TableView 里
Now, this should have worked,
那么 这个本来是应该奏效
right?
对不对
But the reason we're getting
但是现在出现了错误
errors, here, is because the
原因在于
NSItemProvider does not
NSItemProvider 没有识别出
recognize my ContactCard class.
我的 ContactCard 分类
So, we need to do a little work
所以 我们需要再做
to conform to the
一小点工作来
NSItemProvider.
达到 NSItemProvider 的要求
Let's look at the ContactCard
我们再看看
class, again.
ContactCard 分类
And here, I'm going to implement
我在这里将要执行
the NSItemProviderReading
NSItemProviderReading
protocol.
协议
This will tell the
这个操作将会告诉
NSItemProvider that I can read
NSItemProvider  我可以
data that it provides.
读取它提供的数据
Now, I need to specify the types
现在 我需要指定我可以
of identifiers that I can read.
读取的标识符类别
My ContactCard class can read
我的 ContactCard 分类
either a vCard, or it can read
要么可读取 vCard
plain text.
要么可读取纯文本
Note that these need to be
但是注意 这些需要
specified in descending order of
按照精准程度的降序先后
fidelity.
而确定
If we specified plain text
如果我们把纯文本确定为首选
first, then we would always get
那我们总是会
called back for plain text.
回调出纯文本
Even when a more rich vCard type
哪怕有更复杂的vCard类
was available.
可用
So, after we've specified the
所以 当我们指定了
types we can read, we're going
我们可读取的类型以后
to set up an initializer where
我们将创建一个初始化器 通过它
we'll actually read the data
我们真正能够从 itemProvider 里
from the itemProvider.
读取数据
One of the arguments in this
类型标识符是
initializer is the
这个初始化器的
typeIdentifier.
参数之一
So, I can use that to figure out
我可以通过它来弄清楚
what type of data I received.
我收到的数据是哪种类型
If I got a vCard, I'll use a
如果我拿到的是 vCard
helper method to set the phone
我将运用辅助方法来
number, picture, and all the
设置手机号码 照片以及
other information I need.
其他所有我需要的信息
If I just got plain text, I'm
如果我只拿到纯文本
going to set the name for my
那么我将给联系人卡片
contact card.
设置姓名
Now, when we run this, those
现在 当我们运行它时
errors are resolved.
这些错误都得到了解决
This is because the
这是因为
NSItemProvider understands our
NSItemProvider 现在读懂了
class, now.
我们的分类
So, this time, I can drag and
那么这次 我可以从右侧的
name from the Contacts app on
通讯录中拖出一个姓名
the right, and drop it into my
加以命名
app.
再放到我的 App 里
As you can see, we loaded the
大家可以看见 我们载入了
name, phone number, as well as
这个联系人的姓名、电话
the photo for this contact.
以及照片
Note that we can still drag out
注意 我们仍可以再次
plain text, like from the
从提醒事项等 App 里
Reminders app, again.
拖出纯文本  像是从备忘录 App 里拖出来一样
And this works, because our
这能够管用
ContactCard class not only
是因为我们的 ContactCard 类
handles vCards, but it also
不仅可以处理 vCard
handles plain text.
还可以处理纯文本
So, this is what we wanted.
这是我们想要的结果
And our users really like this
而且我们的用户非常喜欢
feature.
这一功能
But now, we have another feature
但是现在 我们收到了另一个
request.
功能请求
They want the ability to drag
他们希望能够从我们的 App 中
out contacts from our app and
拖出联系人然后再
drop it into other apps.
放到其他的 App 里
In order to implement that,
为了实现这一功能
we'll have to conform to another
我们必须遵循另一协议
protocol called
协议名称是
NSItemProviderWriting protocol.
NSItemProviderWriting
As part of this protocol, I'll
作为此协议的一部分
specify the types of identifiers
我将明确我可以编写的
that I can write.
标识符类型
My class can again, write either
我的分类可以再编写
a vCard or plain text.
vCard 或纯文本
After this, we need to specify a
在这之后 我们需要指定
loadData method.
一个 loadData 方法
In this method, we'll create the
在这个方法里 我们将创建出
data that we want to provide to
自己想要提供给 itemProvider
the itemProvider.
的数据
So, based on the type
因此 根据类型标识符
identifier, I can create
我可以创建出
different types of data and I'll
不同类型的数据 而且
just pass it to the
我只需把它传输给
completionHandler.
completionHandler
Now, we have completed the
现在 我们已经完成了
implementation for the
NSItemProviderWriting 协议
NSItemProviderWriting protocol.
的执行
There's just one last thing to
现在只剩下最后一件事
do.
要做
We need to go back into our
我们需要回到
TableViewController and tell the
我们的 TableViewController
TableView that it can be used to
并告诉 TableView 它可被用来
drag out items.
拖拽出项目
To do this, I'll implement the
为了实现这一点 我将执行
TableViewDragDelegate.
TableViewDragDelegate
We need to set this delegate,
我们还需对这一委托
too.
进行设置
And for this delegate, we'll
对于这个委托
implement one method called
我们将执行一个名为
itemsForBeginning session.
itemsForBeginning Session的方法
In this method, I'm going to
在该方法中
create an itemProvider.
我将创建一个itemProvider
And you can see that I'm able to
大家可以看到
pass a ContactCard object
我能够把一个 ContactCard 对象
directly to the itemProvider's
直接传输给 itemProvider 的
initializer.
初始化器
This works only because we
这之所以可行 仅仅是因为
implemented the
我们执行了
NSItemProviderWriting protocol.
NSItemProviderWriting 协议
Let's run this code, now.
现在 让我们来运行这个代码
And I would like to share a
我想要在短信里
contact with my colleague on
把一个联系人共享给
Messages.
我的同事
So, let me drag out Dinesh's
那么 我就拖出 Dinesh 的
contact and drop it.
名片并放进去
As you can see, we were able to
如你所见 我们可以
send out the name, phone number,
发送姓名 电话号码
as well as the photo.
以及照片
Which is what we were trying to
这正是我们想要
accomplish.
实现的效果
So, now we have learned how the
现在 我们已经了解到
NSItemProvider reading and
NSItemProvider 的读取及编写协议
writing protocols can be used to
是怎样运用自定义类对象
transfer data using custom class
从而实现数据转移的
These are really powerful
这是两个非常强大的协议
protocols and we think you'll
我们认为
find them extremely useful when
当你在自己的 App 里
you implement drag and drop in
进行拖放时 将会发现
your own apps.
这些协议极其有用
Up next, Dave will cover some
接下来 Dave 将来介绍
advanced topics.
一些高阶主题
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Tanu.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Tanu
So, cool. All right.
太酷了 好
Next, we're going to cover some
接下来 我们将介绍
advanced topics.
一些高阶主题
These are just some collection
它们只是一些
of things that is very good to
非常值得了解的信息
know, when you're going to
如果你想要
polish your app so that it
改善你的App 以便让它
shines in the drag-and-drop
在拖放环境中显得
environment.
出众的话
The first thing we're going to
我们首先要介绍的是
cover is data marshaling.
数据编组
So, if you look at the
当你在 iOS 11 里查看
NSItemProvider API in iOS 11,
NSItemProvider API 时
you'll discover that there are
你会发现其中有
three ways you can provide data.
三种提供数据的方式
You can provide data as a data
显然 你可以用数据对象的形式
object, obviously.
来提供数据
But you can also provide data as
但你也可以采用文件储存里的
a file or a folder on your file
文件或文件夹的形式
storage.
来提供数据
Third, you can provide the data
第三 你可以将数据作为
as a reference into a File
File Provider
Provider.
的引用
We'll talk about File Providers
我们稍后会进一步
more, later.
讨论 File Provider
Similarly, the receiver of the
类似地 数据接收器
data can retrieve data in three
也有三种不同的
different ways.
数据检索方式
They can copy it as their own NS
它们可以将数据复制为
data object.
自己的 NSData 对象
They can copy a file or a folder
可以将文件或文件夹复制到
into their container.
它们的容器里
And they can attempt to open the
还可以尝试在本地
file in place.
打开相应文件
So, three ways to provide data,
所以 有三种方式可以提供数据
and three ways to consume it.
也有三种方式去使用数据
What do you have to do to make
你需要做好哪些事情
sure that data transfer happens
才能确保数据的流畅传输
seamlessly, and that the data is
并且确保能够
made available in the correct
以正确的格式
format?
提供数据
Well, the good news is you have
嗯 好消息  你现在
to do nothing.
什么也不用做
We do it for you.
我们来替你做
Data marshaling makes sure that
数据编组可以确保
the provider of the data can
数据提供者能够
provide and consume the
通过自身感觉
information in the way that's
最为便利的方式
most convenient for them.
来提供和使用信息
If you provide a file and then,
如果你提供了一个文件  然后
you consume it as a data, we
要把它作为数据来使用
will read the file into an
我们就会为你把这份文件
NSData object for you.
读取为 NSData 对象
If you provide an NSData and you
如果你提供的是 NSData 并
ask for a file copy, we'll write
请求文件副本 我们将把它
it to file storage and give you
写入文件储存并
your L reference to it.
把你对它的 L 引用发给你
If they provided a folder and
如果你提供的是文件夹
you asked for NSData, we will
并且请求 NSData 我们将
zip up the contents of the
压缩文件夹内容
folder and give you an NSData of
然后把压缩文件的
the zip file.
NSData给你
And if they provide a reference
如果你提供
to a file provider and you ask
一个 File Provider 的引用
for a file copy, we will call in
并请求文件副本 我们将
the promises for the file
为 File Provider
provider and make a copy on your
调入承诺  并替你
behalf.
生成副本
All right.
好
So, we've seen how progress and
我们已经了解到
cancellation worked from the
进度和取消是如何
consumer side.
由数据使用者这一方来执行
So, I want to talk a little bit
接下来 我想要简要地谈一下
about how progress and
进度和取消
cancellation works on the
如何作用于
provider's side.
数据提供者的
I'm going to show you a block of
现在 我将向你展示
code, here.
一个代码块
Don't worry that it's a dense
看到这个密集的代码块
block of code, because I'm going
别担心
to highlight the parts that are
因为我会突出显示
most important.
最重要的部分
This is a loadData
这是为 NSItemProviderWriting
implementation for our
执行的
NSItemProviderWriting.
loadData
In which you are going to use a
你在这期间将会运用
dataLoader object to
dataLoader 对象去
incrementally load data.
递增加载数据
To provide progress and
为了提供对进度和
cancellation support, the first
取消功能的支持
thing you have to do is create
你要做的第一件事就是
your own progress object.
创建你自己的进度对象
In this case, we're creating one
在这个例子中 我们将创建一个
with a UnitCount of 100 as a
UnitCount 为 100% 的
percentage.
对象
On that progress object, you can
在这个进度对象上
attach a cancellationHandler
你可以附加一个 cancellationHandler
that will be called when the
当你的数据使用者
consumer of your data calls
要求取消进度对象的实例时
cancel on their instance of the
cancellationHandler
progress object.
将被调用
In this case, all we're doing is
在这个例子中 我们所做的一切操作
setting a local variable from
都是在将局部变量
true to false, which should stop
从True设置为 Flase
the dataLoader from loading the
这会阻止 dataLoader 加载
next chunk.
下一分块
As the dataLoader progresses,
在 dataLoader 进度开展时
you can update the
你可以在你的进度对象上
completedUnitCount on your
更新 completedUnitCount
progress object to drive the
以便驱动
progress indicator on the
接收方的
receiver.
进度指示器
And of course, you have to
当然 你必须
return your own progress object
返回你自己的进度对象
so that we can type it over to
以便我们将其改写到
the other side.
另一侧
All right.
好
Switching gears, now.
现在换个话题
We're going to talk about some
我们另外再谈一些功能
features that help you to polish
能在你创建成套 App 时
your data representations when
帮你改进数据表示方式
creating suites of apps.
的功能
So, we're going to talk about
下面 我们来聊一聊
Per-Representation Visibility.
Per-Representation Visibility
Remember, you can provide
记住 你可以在
multiple representations of your
NSItemProvider 里提供
data in NSItemProvider.
多种数据表示形式
You can restrict the visibility
你可以将
of each representation to either
每种表示的可见性
visible to only your source
限制为仅对你的源应用
application.
可见
To the applications that are
它对你组内指定的应用
assigned by your team, so in
是可见的
your suite of apps, or to
这是在你的应用套件里的情况
everyone.
或对所有应用都可见
You can use this property to
你可以运用这个属性
hide private types that you are
来隐藏你正在
rapidly maintaining with
使用各种版本的应用套件
versions of your application
而迅速累积的
suite.
个人类型
So, you don't have to worry
因此 你不必担心
about third parties serializing
第三方会将你的数据
your data to disc.
序列化至磁盘上
In a similar vein, you have a
以此类推 你在
team data property on
NSItemProvider 上
NSItemProvider.
有一个 teamData 属性
This is an eight kilobyte data
这是一个8千字节的数据块
block that you can attach
你可以通过一个
through an NSItemProvider.
NSItemProvider 将它附加
They are only visible to other
它们只对你组内
applications in your team.
的其他应用可见
You can use this to improve your
你可以运用这一点
UI in any way you see fit,
用你自己认为合适的方式  在拖动过程中
during a drag.
改良你的 UI
This is metadata, and can be
这是元数据
retrieved even before the user
它甚至在用户抬手示意之前
lifts their finger.
就可以被检索到
All right.
好
There is a suggestedName
在 NSItemProvider 上
property on the NSItemProvider.
有一个 suggestedName 属性
If you provide a string for the
如果你给 suggestedName
suggested name, we will use it
提供一个字符串  我们会
as a file name when the
在检索器把你的数据
retriever writes your data to
写入磁盘时  把这个字符串用作
disc.
文件名
This is especially useful, of
当然  你在提供 NSData 的
course, when you're providing an
时候  这一点也就
NSData.
格外有用
And the last property I want to
我想介绍的
talk about is Preferred
最后一个属性
Presentation Size.
是 preferredPresentationSize
This is a CG size property that
这是一个 CG 规格大小的属性
you can provide to give a hint
你可以通过它来
to the receiver about how big
提示接收者
your representation's going to
你的表示形式在展开过后
end up after they've laid out.
的规格大小
This is used, for example, by
例如 通过邮件 App 对
Mail, to drop images into the
这一属性的运用
Mail Compose sheet, into the
图片可以被拖进邮件撰写表单
destination layout, even before
拖进目的地布局  这一切甚至在
the data arrives.
数据到达前就已发生
And finally, I'm going to talk
最后 我将聊一聊
about File Providers.
File Provider
So, File Providers is a whole
File Provider 本身就是
other topic, on its own.
另一个完整的主题
But a short summary can be said
但我们也可以做出下述的
as follows.
简要概括
A File Provider is an app
File Provider是一个
extension.
应用扩展
This app extension allows data
举个例子
transfer from a network
这一应用扩展
download, for example, to
能够允许数据通过
continue even if your main
网络下载而传送
application has been terminated.
即使你的主应用已被终止
For long running drags, this is
对于操作时间较长的拖拽而言
especially useful.
这一点特别有用
Because as the user waits for a
因为当用户在等待下载时
download to occur, they may
他们可能会
navigate away from your app, and
从你的 App 引导到别的地方
your app could get terminated.
而你的 App 可能会被终止
If you provide a URL to a file
如果你向某个 File Provider 容器里
inside a File Provider
的某个文件提供
container, the File Provider
一个 URL
extension will continue to serve
File Provider 扩展将继续执行
the data transfer request, even
数据传送请求
though your UI application is
即使你的 UI 引用
terminated.
已被终止
And that increases the chances
这增加了
that your data is going to be
你的数据得以成功
transferred successfully.
传送的几率
And as an added bonus, if you
除此之外 如果你
create a File Provider that
创建的 File Provider
appears in the file's app, we
出现在文件的应用里
will allow you to drag and drop
我们将允许你拖放
URLs that can be opened in
可以在本地打开的
place.
URL
Which means that multiple
这就意味着
applications can access that
多个应用可以访问同一文件
same file, instead of getting
而不是各自获取
their own copy.
它的副本
There's some really great
接下来的两个议程
information available in the
将提供一些
following two sessions.
非常棒的信息
I highly recommend that you
如果你们对在拖放环境中
attend them, if you are
提供 File Provider
interested in providing File
感兴趣的话
Providers in the context of drag
我强烈建议
and drop.
大家去参加
All right.
好
Next, we're going to take a look
接下来 我们再看一下
at what we can do with files in
在拖放过程中我们可以
drag and drop, by having Tanu do
对文件进行怎样的操作
another demo.
Tanu 可以再次演示一下
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Hope you are ready for
&gt;&gt; 希望大家已经准备好观看
another demo.
下一个演示了
In the previous demo, we saw how
在先前的演示中我们看到
we could drag and drop simple
如何拖放简单的
system objects, as well as
系统对象 以及
custom class objects.
自定义类对象
Now, let's see how we can handle
现在 让我们来看看应该怎样处理
files.
文件
We'll look at our customer's
我们将再一次查看我们
app, again.
客户的 App
And for some people, here, we
对于有些听众  今天
have additional data.
我们要说说附加数据
Like for Adam, we know what
例如 Adam 我们知道
products he's purchased.
他买了哪些产品
Now, I would like to drag out
现在 我想要把这个文件
this file into another app and
拖拽到另一个 App 中
potentially edit it, there.
并有可能在那个 App 里编辑这份文件
To implement this, I'll look at
为了实现这一点 我将
the ContactDetailsViewController
在我的客户 App 里
in my customer's app.
查看 ContactDetailsViewController
Over here, we will add a drag
在这儿 我们要把一个
interaction to the attachment
拖动交互添加到
image that we just saw.
我们刚刚看到的附件图片上
Let's also, implement the Drag
我们还要再执行一下这里的
Interaction Delegate, right
拖动交互委托
here, because we have set the
因为我们已经将
delegate to self.
委托设置为 self
You may have heard of the drag
你们可能在之前的会议上
interaction delegate in previous
已经听说过
sessions.
拖动交互委托
If you're interested in learning
如果你有兴趣了解
more about this delegate, I
更多关于这一委托的信息
would encourage you to check out
我建议你去观看
the video for Session 213 on
213号会议的视频
Mastering Drag and Drop.
它的主题是如何掌握拖放功能
For the purposes of this demo,
不过在本次演示中
though, we'll only look at one
我们只准备介绍一种方法
method, called itemsForBeginning
它的名称是 itemsForBeginning
session.
session
In this method, we'll create a
在这个方法中 我们将创建
new itemProvider, and on the
一个新的 itemProvider 并且
itemProvider we'll call a method
在这个 itemProvider 上调用
called
一个名为 registerFileRepresentation
registerFileRepresentation.
的方法
This method takes four
这个方法包含了四个
arguments.
参数
The first one is the type
第一个是
identifier.
类型标识符
Our attachment file was actually
我们的附件实际上是
an image.
一张图片
So, I've set the type identifier
所以 我已经将类型标识符设为
to JPEG.
JPEG
The second parameter is file
第二个参数是
options.
文件选项
This can be used to specify if
它可以用于确定
we want other apps to open our
我们是想让其他 App
file in place, or if we want
在本地打开我们的文件 还是
them to make a copy.
让它们对文件进行复制
We would like them to open our
我们想让其他 App
file in place, so we can see the
在本地打开我们的文件 这样可以看到
changes they make.
它们所做的改动
The third parameter is
第三个参数是
visibility.
可见性
This can be your own process,
它可以设置为对你自己
your team, or all.
你的组  或所有的应用可见
I've just set it to all.
我刚才已经设置成对所有应用可见了
Finally, we have the
最后一个参数
completionHandler.
是 completionHandler
And we are going to pass the URL
我们将把 URL 文件
file into this
传递给这个
completionHandler.
completionHandler
So, let's get the URL, first.
那么 我们先获取 URL
Over here, I have a helper
在这个地方 我有一个
method that grabs the URL for my
辅助方法可以从 File Provider
file from a File Provider.
获取我的文件的 URL
I need to use a File Provider
只有当我在本地打开文件时
only when I'm opening files in
才需要使用
place.
File Provider
If I wanted other apps to make a
如果我想要其他 App
copy, then I do not need a File
复制文件 那就无需使用
Provider.
File Provider
I could have just provided a
只要提供一个本地URL
local URL.
就可以了
We'll pass this URL to the
我们将把这个 URL 传递给
completionHandler.
completionHandler
Now, our itemProvider is set up.
现在 我们的 itemProvider 已设置好了
And we can use this to create a
可以用它来创建
drag item.
一个拖动项
With this, the code is ready to
有了它 这个代码就可以
run.
运行了
So, now I can drag out this
所以 我现在可以拖出这个
file.
文件
And let me open another app
让我来打开另一个 App
where I'll drop it.
作为拖放的目的地
So, we'll drag out the data,
那么 我们把数据拖出来
drop it into a document editing
再放入一个文档编辑的
app.
APP里
And I'm concerned now, that Adam
我现在担心
is buying a lot of products from
Adam 正从我们的竞品那里
our competitor.
大量购买产品
So, let me highlight this and
所以 我要圈出这一点
save these changes.
并且把改动保存下来
So, since our document editing
由于我们的文档编辑 App
app actually used the URL
实际上使用了用户 App
provided by the customer's app,
提供的 URL
you'll see that we got the same
你将看到我们用户的 App
changes back in our customer's
也有了相同的
app.
改动
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Glad you like that.
很高兴你们能喜欢这个功能
We've now seen how to handle
现在 我们已经了解了
system objects, custom class
如何处理系统对象、自定义类对象
objects, as well as files.
以及各种文件
We have a wide range of APIs
我们有众多类型的 API
that you can adopt.
供你使用
And we look forward to seeing
我们很期待看到
how you use them.
大家如何使用它们
Back to Dave, to summarize.
接下来 有请 Dave 做个总结
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Tanu.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Tanu
All right.
好
Let's recap.
我们来概括一下
During this session, we've seen
在本次会议中 我们了解到
how an NSItemProvider is
NSItemProvider 对于
fundamental to the way data is
不同应用之间借助拖放功能
transferred between applications
而传输数据的方式
in Drag and Drop.
起到了何等重要的作用
We've seen how multiple
我们还了解到
representations allow your
多重表示方法怎样能让
applications to maximize
你的应用与其他应用
compatibility with other
实现最大限度的
applications.
兼容性
And we've seen how data is
我们了解到数据是
transferred asynchronously with
怎样以可取消的方式
progress in a cancellable
来实现规定进度的
fashion.
异步传输
We've also seen how
我们还了解到
NSItemProvider reading and
NSItemProvider 读取和编写协议
writing protocols allow you to
是怎样让你
make model classes that work
创建能够和拖放 UI 代码
well with drag-and-drop UI code.
完美配合的模型类
And how visibility and team data
以及可见性和teamData
allows you to create suites of
还有  如何能让你创建
apps that work in especially
在拖放过程中
well together during drag and
格外适用的
drop.
应用套件
And finally, we've seen how File
最后 我们了解到
Providers afford you the ability
File Provider 是如何
to open files in place as the
让你能够通过拖放功能
result of drag and drop.
最终在本地打开文件
For more information, please
想要了解更多信息 请访问
visit our developer website,
我们的开发者网站
Session 227.
227号会议
And I highly encourage you to
我强烈建议大家
attend the File Provider related
参加有关 File Provider 的会议
sessions, today and tomorrow, to
就在今明两天
learn more about how to create
去了解更多关于怎样
File Providers for your own
为你自己的应用创建
applications.
File Provider 的信息
If you haven't seen the first
如果你没有参加
three sessions on Drag and Drop,
关于拖放功能的前三场会议
I highly recommend that you
我强烈建议大家
review them on video.
观看视频回放
Thank you, for your attention,
感谢关注
and have a great WWDC.
祝你们在 WWDC 有所收获